<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Second Conference on Computational Humanities Research on Computational Humanities Research 2021</title>
    <link>http://2021.computational-humanities-research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Second Conference on Computational Humanities Research on Computational Humanities Research 2021</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 11:12:14 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://2021.computational-humanities-research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Past Events</title>
      <link>http://2021.computational-humanities-research/archive/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 16:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://2021.computational-humanities-research/archive/</guid>
      <description>CHR2020 CHR2020 was a three-day workshop held on November 18 to 20, 2020. The program committee and organizers accepted 29 papers, which have been published with CEUR-WS: http://ceur-ws.org/Vol-2723/. See https://2020.computational-humanities-research.org/ for more information about CHR2020.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organizers and Programme Committee</title>
      <link>http://2021.computational-humanities-research/people/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 15:59:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://2021.computational-humanities-research/people/</guid>
      <description>Organizers  Tara Andrews, University of Vienna Manuel Burghardt, Computational Humanities, University of Leipzig Giovanni Colavizza, University of Amsterdam Maud Ehrmann, École Polytechnique Fédérale de Lausanne Folgert Karsdorp, Meertens Institute Mike Kestermont, CLiPS Enrique Manjavacas, Universiteit Antwerpen Barbara McGillivray, Alan Turing Institute/University of Cambridge George Mikros, University of Athens Adina Nerghes, Wageningen University &amp;amp; Research, Kristoffer Nielbo, University of Aarhus Michael Piotrowski, University of Lausanne Melvin Wevers, University of Amsterdam Joris van Zundert, Huygens ING - KNAW  Programme Committee  Alberto Acerbi, University of Bristol Maristella Agosti, University of Padua Tara Andrews, University of Vienna Adrien Barbaresi, BBAW Andreas Baumann, University of Vienna Kaspar Beelen, The Alan Turing Institute Elli Bleeker, KNAW Federica Bologna, Università di Bologna Emanuela Boros, Université de La Rochelle Estelle Bunout, University of Luxembourg Manuel Burghardt, Computational Humanities, University of Leipzig Frédéric Clavert, C2DH / Université du Luxembourg Giovanni Colavizza, University of Amsterdam Mariona Coll Ardanuy, The Alan Turing Institute Andreas van Cranenburgh, University of Groningen Thierry Declerck, DFKI GmbH Antoine Doucet, University of La Rochelle Marten During, C2DH / Université du Luxembourg Maud Ehrmann, École Polytechnique Fédérale de Lausanne Marieke van Erp, KNAW Humanities Cluster Pieter Francois, University of Oxford Heather Froehlich, The Pennsylvania State University Simon Hengchen, University of Gothenburg Leah Henrickson, University of Leeds J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Important Dates</title>
      <link>http://2021.computational-humanities-research/dates/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 12:53:21 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://2021.computational-humanities-research/dates/</guid>
      <description>NEW! Submission deadline: July 9, 2021
Notification to authors: September 3, 2021 
Camera-ready: September 17, 2021 
Conference: November 17 - November 19, 2021</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accepted Papers</title>
      <link>http://2021.computational-humanities-research/papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 08:55:52 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://2021.computational-humanities-research/papers/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advisory Board</title>
      <link>http://2021.computational-humanities-research/advisory-board/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 21:22:17 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://2021.computational-humanities-research/advisory-board/</guid>
      <description>Tara Andrews - University of Vienna, Austria Maud Ehrmann - EPFL, Switzerland Leah Henrickson - Loughborough University, UK Mike Kestemont - University of Antwerp, Belgium Barbara McGillivray - University of Cambridge and The Alan Turing Institute, UK George Mikros - National and Kapodistrian University of Athens, Greece Kristoffer Nielbo - Aarhus University, Denmark Michael Piotrowski - University of Lausanne, Switzerland Tatjana Scheffler - University of Potsdam, Germany Ted Underwood - University of Illinois, U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join the Community</title>
      <link>http://2021.computational-humanities-research/community/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 11:12:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://2021.computational-humanities-research/community/</guid>
      <description>We cordially invite you and other interested parties to join the Computational Humanities Research forum! The forum serves as an asynchronous platform to discuss all ideas and questions related to computational humanities research. These can be in-depth discussions about fundamental topics and questions of the discipline, or very practical ones, for example about how best to tackle a certain technical (coding) problem. And everything in between. Come join!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join the Community</title>
      <link>http://2021.computational-humanities-research/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 11:12:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://2021.computational-humanities-research/contact/</guid>
      <description>Community Please join our Computational Humanities Research forum! The forum serves as an asynchronous platform to discuss all ideas and questions related to computational humanities research. These can be in-depth discussions about fundamental topics and questions of the discipline, or very practical ones, for example about how best to tackle a certain technical (coding) problem. And everything in between. Come join!
Contact For questions, ideas, or support, contact the organizers or drop us a line on the forum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call for Papers</title>
      <link>http://2021.computational-humanities-research/cfp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 11:11:58 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://2021.computational-humanities-research/cfp/</guid>
      <description>Registration is now open
In the arts and humanities, the use of computational, statistical, and mathematical approaches has considerably increased in recent years. This research is characterized by the use of formal methods and the construction of explicit, computational models. This includes quantitative, statistical approaches, but also more generally computational methods for processing and analyzing data, as well as theoretical reflections on these approaches. Despite the undeniable growth of this research area, many scholars still struggle to find suitable research-oriented venues to present and publish computational work that does not lose sight of traditional modes of inquiry in the arts and humanities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conference</title>
      <link>http://2021.computational-humanities-research/conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 11:11:58 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://2021.computational-humanities-research/conference/</guid>
      <description>Registration is now open
Accepted papers  Benjamin Lee, Joshua Ortiz Baco, Sarah Salter and Jim Casey: Navigating the Mise-en-Page: Interpretive Machine Learning Approaches to the Visual Layouts of Multi-Ethnic Periodicals
  Oliver Hellwig, Sven Sellmer and Sebastian Nehrdich: Obtaining More Expressive Corpus Distributions for Standardized Ancient Languages
  Jurian Baas, Mehdi Dastani and Ad Feelders: Entity Matching in Digital Humanities Knowledge Graphs
  Iiro Tiihonen, Mikko Tolonen and Leo Lahti: Probabilistic Analysis of Early Modern British Book Prices</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
